American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIi. 1897 APS.Archives.IIi APS.Archives.IIi
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 14, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Bonaparte, Roland, prince, 1858-1924
    Paris, L.S.: C. Belhatte 1p., end. Concerns missing Proceedings.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 14, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L. 3p. Encs. wanting Sends letter from Mercer. Explains charges for correcting galleys.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 15, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Cleemann, Richard A. (Richard Alsop), 1840-1912
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 16, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. 4p. Will offer no communications since his paper on evolution was insulted.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 16, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Fraley, Joseph Cresson, ca. 1848-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Will prepare obituary of A. Biddle.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, April 16, 1897; 8x5; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Will prepare obituary of Hartshorne.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 17, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Wilson Brothers & Co.
    Phila., A.L.S.: Jos[eph] M[iller] Wilson 1p. Cost of stairway in Hall.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 18, 1897; 8x5; Greene, Wm. H. (William Houston), 1853-1918
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Sends some "rubbish."
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April 18, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Forwards postal card. Health improves.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, April 19, 1897; 12x8; Alve, Clarence
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his theory about the canals on Mars.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 19, 1897; 8x5; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1832-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will read paper on "Relation of the pentagonal dodecahedron found near Marietta, Ohio to Shamanism" at next meeting. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36 pp. 179-183. Refers to F. H. Cushing.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1897; 10-1/2x8; University of Pennsylvania. Biology dept.
    Phila., A.L.S.: Edwin G[rant] Conklin 1p. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1897; 11x8-1/2, 10x5-1/2; University of Wisconsin
    Madison, Wis., A.L.S.:Walter M. Smith, Libn. 2p., end. Enc. of 2p. printed list Exchange of publications. Sends check list.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 20, 1897; 10x8-1/2; Winand, Paul A. N.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting. Proof returned.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 23, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Cassel, Daniel Kolb, b. 1820
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Benjamin Rittenhouse died in 1825.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], April 23, 1897; 8x5; Geikie, Archibald, Sir, 1835-1924
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns talk before A.P.S. Refers to W. Pepper.
  - Letter to [William] Pepper, April 23, 1897; 8x5; Geikie, Archibald, Sir, 1835-1924
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns talk before A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 23, 1897; 6-1/4x4-1/2; Miller, G. A. (George Abram), 1863-1951
    Paris, A.L.S. 3p. Has sent MSS. on mathematics.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 26, 1897; 10x8; Carson, Hampton L. (Hampton Lawrence), 1852-1929
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Introduces A.E. Turner.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 26, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Wilson Brothers & Co.
    Phila., A.L.S.: Jos[eph] M[iller] Wilson 2p. Concerns stairway in Hall. Refers to Pepper, Pettit.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, April 27, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 7p. Will send more MS. of his paper on excavations in Florida soon. Refers to R.S. Culin. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to [Charlemagne] Tower, April 28, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. Asks him to expedite European exchanges while minister to Austria.
  - Invitation to Edward [sic] Grant Conklin, to dine and meet Sir Archibald Geikie, April 28, [1897]; 7x4-1/2; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    [Phila.], N. in 3d person 1p.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, April 29, 1897; 11x8; Kennelly, Arthur E. (Arthur Edwin), 1861-1939
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Houston and Kennelly 1p. Enc. wanting Sends remarks by Macfarlane on their paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 30, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Western News Company
    Chicago, Typed L. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Asks about subscription to Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 30, 1897; 10x8-1/2; Winand, Paul A. N.
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerns length of his paper.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, April, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, [Pa.], Sunday A.L.S. 2p. Concerns illustrations for paper on sloth. "I have just come from Prof. Cope's - as distressed as I can be". For printed paper, see: APS Proceeding; Vol. 36, PP. 36-70.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, May 1, 1897; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Tower, Charlemagne, 1848-1923
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Will try to expedite European exchanges
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 3, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will prepare obituary for H.D. Gregory.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 3, 1897; 10-1/4x8-1/4
    London, Typed L.S. with stamp: Rob[er]t Harrison 1p., end. Concerns request for set of Challenger reports.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 3, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for nomination papers. Invites O.C.S Carter and H.F. Keller to next meeting.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, May 3, 1897; 11x8-1/2; University of Wisconsin
    Madison, Wis., A.L.S.: Walter M. Smith 2p., end. Exchange of publications. Refers to G.C. Comstock, Washburn Observatory.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, May 4, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; A.C. McClurg & Co.
    Chicago, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Book order.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 4, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for invitation for J.F. Holt to next meeting.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, May 5, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Columbia University
    New York, Typed L.S.: Geo[rge] H[all] Baker, Librarian 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 7, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Offers paper by R.H. Mathews on Australian rock-carvings. Refers to Academy of natural sciences. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 195-208.
  - Letter to George H[enry] Horn, May 8, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Stanford University, A.L.S. 2p. Submits G.H. Ashley's paper on Arkansas geology. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp.217-318.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 8, 1897; 3-1/4x5-1/4; A. Dulau & Co.
    London, L. on postal card 1p. Purchase of Proceedings.
  - Letter to J. Mimis [sic] Hays, May 8, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Calls meeting of Committee on Revision of the Laws.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 8, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Packard, A. S. (Alpheus Spring), 1839-1905
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends proofs which he wants made into electrotypes.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 8, 1897; 6x8-1/2; Washburn Observatory
    Madison, [Wis.], Typed L.S.: Geo[rge] C[ary] Comstock 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 8, May 15, 1897; 10x8; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Typed L. 2 items 2p., end. Concerns missing issues from its set of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 9, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Doolittle, C. L. (Charles Leander), 1843-1919
    A.L.S. 2p. Speaks to Percival Lowell's nomination for membership.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 10, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns corrected membership list. Refers to d'Auria's talk on stellar dynamics.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 10, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns preparation of revised membership list. Refers to Phillips.
  - Letter to J[sic] Minis Hays, May 10, 1897; 13-1/4x8-1/4; New South Wales. Dept. of Mines and Agriculture
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 11, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Foote, Albert E., Co.
    Phila., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Cannot supply the National Geographic.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Innis [sic] Hays, May 11, 1897; 10-1/2x8; United States. Post Office Dept.
    Washington, Typed L.S.:R. L. Maddox 1p. Concerns amendment to rules of International Postal Congress.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 13, 1897; 10-1/4x8; Abbe, Cleveland, 1838-1916
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Inquires about documents on the early history of meteorology. Refers to J.P. Espy and A.D. Bache.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 13, 1897; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. Enc. wanting Sends part of MS. of his paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 13, 1897; 8x5; Schäffer, Charles, 1838-1903
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Postpones nomination of George Vaux Jr. and G.B. Keen.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 13, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Société royale de géographie d'Anvers
    Antwerp, A.L.S.: Edm. Lombaerts 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Persifer [sic] Frazer, May 14, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila. Typed L. 1p. Has no duplicate set of rocks from first Penna. geological survey.
  - Minutes of the meeting of the Officers and the Council, May 14, 1897; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 1p. Rough notes.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 14, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Jastrow, Morris, 1861-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. Asks for credentials as representative to the Congress of Orientalists.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 14, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Literary and Philosophical Society of Liverpool
    Liver-pool, A.L.S.: I. Maxwell McMaster 3p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 14, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, [Mass.] A.L.S. 1p. Asks about copies of his paper. Refers to Horn' s "extraordinary improvement."
  - Receipt for botanical collections deposited by the A.P.S. in accord with resolution of May 14 [sic, 13] 1897, May 14, June 21, 1897; 9x6, 11x8-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    [Phila.] D.S.: Stewardson Brown 1p. Enc. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Cf. Proceedings, v.36, p.316. Enclosure is copy of receipt, end. across face: I have had this chequed ff. & find it correct. Samuel G[ibston] Dixon, President.
  - Letter to William V[incent] McKean, May 15, 1897; 10-1/2x8, 3-3/4x6-1/2; Lewis, William Draper, 1867-1949
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. and add., end. Inquires about Phillips prize. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Telegram to [Isaac] Minis Hays, May 15, 1897; 5-1/4x8; Sajous, Charles E. de M. (Charles Eucharist de Medicis), 1852-1929
    Ambler, Pa., D. 1p. Gives title of his talk on solar heat and universal gravitation. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, p. 319.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 15, 1897; 10-3/4x8; United States. Division of Entomology
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Concerns periodical, "Insect Life."
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, May 15, 1897; 11x8-1/2; University of Wisconsin
    Madison, Wis., A.L.S.: Walter M. Smith 2p., end. Exchange of publications. Refers to Washburn Observatory.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 15, 1897; 10x8-1/2; Winand, Paul A. N.
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Returns revised proof. Refers to Hays.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 16, 1897; 8X5-1/2; Faculté des sciences de Marseille
    Marseille, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. In French Exchange of publications.
  - Telegram to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 16, 1897; 5-1/4x8; Furness, William Henry, 1866-1920
    Wallingford, Pa., D. 1p. Copy Concerns talk on Borneo.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 17, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Lea, Henry Charles, 1825-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 18, 1897; 10x7-1/2; Columbian University
    Washington, Typed L.S.: B. L. Whitman 1p. and end. Acknowledges receipt of Phillips prize circular.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 18, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Harvey, Oscar Jewell, 1851-
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Asks permission to copy documents for his history of Wilkesbarré, Pa.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 19, 1897; 8x5; Society of Arts (Great Britain)
    London, L. 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 19, 1897; 11x8-1/2; The Yale Review
    New Haven, Conn. Typed L.S.: J[ohn] C[hristopher] Schwab 1p. Cannot exchange publications.
  - Letter to W[illiam] H[enry] Wahl, May 20, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add., end. with Wahl's reply. Asks if Franklin Institute has certain serials.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society; Cairo], May 20, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Institut égyptien
    A.L.S.: Léon Vidal 1p., end. Lack Proceedings, No. 147.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 20, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Journal of microscopy and natural science
    Bath, [Eng.], A.L.S.: Alfred Allen 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, May 20, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Rosengarten & Sons
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Gives J.G. Rosengarten's address.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, May 20, 1897; 11-1/4x8-1/2; Snyder, Monroe Benjamin, 1848-1932
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Recommends publication of G.A. Miller's mathematical papers. Refers to E.H. Moore, d'Auria.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 21, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illia]m A. Pickell, with MS. corrections 2p. Concerns charges for printing.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 22, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922
    Stanford University, Cal., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends samples to be used in printing J.P. Smith's separates, "Marine fossils from the coal measures of Arkansas." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 213-285.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 22, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Brown, George Stuart
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 22, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to committee on Franklin Bicentennial Celebration.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], May 22, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Jastrow, Morris, 1861-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Acknowledges receipt of credentials to Congress of Orientalists.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 22, [1897]; Cossmann, Maurice, 1850-1924
    1 postcard. In French.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 24, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting and obituary by Frazer. Refers to obituary of G.W. Biddle and S. Dickson.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 24, 1897; 9x8; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Taped L. 1p. Concerns printing. Refers to Cushing.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 24, 1897; 11x8-1/2, 4-1/2x6; Michigan. Geological Survey
    Houghton, Mich., Typed L.S.: Alfred C[hurch] Lans 1p., end. Enc. of 1p. printed sheet with MS. additions Can obtain Survey Reports from Dept. of Public Instruction
  - Letter to [Persifor] Frazer, May 24, 1897; 9-1/4x6; Morley, Frank, 1860-1937
    Haverford, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Recommends G.A. Miller. Refers to E.H. Moore and F.N. Cole.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, May 24, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    [London], Typed L.S.: Henry Young 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 25, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns resolution by Prime to consider cooperation with Royal Society on its Catalogue of Scientific papers. Written on verso is Fraley's reply. See Fraley to Hays, June 17, 1897.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 25, 1897; 10x8; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    Phila., Printed L.filled in in MS., S.: F[rederick] D[awson] Stone 1p. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 25, 1897; 10-3/4x8; United States. Division of Entomology
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 26, 1897; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Geological Society of London
    London, Printed L. on postal card, filled in in MS., S.: L. L. Belinfante 1p. and add. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Augustus Jay] DuBois, May 26, 1897; 8x5; Phillips, Andrew W. (Andrew Wheeler), 1844-1915
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p., end. Recommends various persons to consult aboutthe theory of groups. On verso is written letter from DuBois to Fraley, [1897].
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 26, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Stone, Frederick D. (Frederick Dawson), 1841-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Introduces Francis M. Brooke.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 27, 1897; 8-1/4x5, 8x3-3/4; Harvey, Oscar Jewell, 1851-
    Wilkesbarré, Pa., A.L.S. 2p. Enc. of printed leaf. Thanks for permission to copy documents. Encloses review of his book, A history of Lodge No. 61, F. and A.M.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 27 to June 30, 1897; 10x8-1/4, 4-1/4x9-1/2; Library Bureau
    Phila., Typed L. 4 items 5p., enc., and add., end. Estimates on shelving and cabinets.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 28, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Ely, Theo. N. (Theodore Newell), 1846-1916
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Inquires about membership dues and fees.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 28, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Will prepare obituary of E.D. Cope.
  - Letter to Edwin Grant Conklin, May 28, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting. Refers to Fraley.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 28, [1897]; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, A.L.S.: A. Hughes 3p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 28, 1897; 11x8-1/2, 9-1/4x6-1/4; University of Chicago
    Chicago, Typed L. 1p. Enc. of 4p. printed leaflet Exchange of publications. Sends its checklist.
  - Letter to J. M. Haze [sic], May 29, 1897; 11-1/4x8-1/2; W.H. Lowdermilk & Co.
    Washington, Typed L. 1p. Quotes "Insect Life."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 29, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Michigan. Dept. of Public Instruction
    Lansing, L. 1p. Cannot supply reports of Geological Survey.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], May 30, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Malacological Society of London
    [London], A.L.S.: E. R. Sykes 1p. Cannot exchange publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, May 30, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, [Pa.], L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends list of anthropological journals which library should have.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 30, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Miller, G. A. (George Abram), 1863-1951
    Paris, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, May 31, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/2; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illiam] A. pickell, Sec'y.2p. Concerns omission of plates from some copies of the Proceedings.
  - Letter to [Frederick Fraley], May, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Mathews, R. H. (Robert Hamilton), 1841-1918
    Parramatta, New South Wales, A.L.S. 5p. concerns publication of his paper on Australian rock carvings. Is sending copies of five other papers for library. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 195-208.
  - Letter to [Edwin Grant] Conklin, June 1, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting. Refers to W. Pepper.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 1, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Returns proofs of Mathews' article on Australian rock-carvings. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 195-208.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 1, 1897; 8-1/2x5; Massachusetts Historical Society
    Boston, A.L.S.: Samuel A[bott] Green 1p. Change of address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 1, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Science
    New York, L. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns APS order for back issues.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 2, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Campbell, Irvin E.
    Richmond, Va., A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to E[dwin] G[rant] Conklin, June 2, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns the Cope Memorial Meeting. Refers to H. Allen.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 2, 1897; 11x8-3/4; Trübner, Karl J.
    Strassburg, Typed L.S. 1p., end. by Frazer to Hays. Enc. wanting. Sends copy of APS description in Minerva for correction.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 3, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Brooke, Francis M.
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends publications of Valley Forge Commission.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, June 3, 1897; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Appoints W. Pepper as A.P.S. representative to Cope Memorial Meeting.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, June 3, 1897; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    London, A.L.S. 4p. Has given Leads 1729 Almanac to Ellis & Elvey for rebinding. Refers to exchanges with British Museum and the French academies. For almanac, see 529.5/L52/1729.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 3, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p., end. Concerns packages forwarded to Europe.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, June 3, 1897; 3x5-1/4; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS. on postal card 1p. and add. Cannot supply Vol. 3 of Misc. Collections.
  - Letter to [Edwin Grant] Conklin, June 4, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting. Suggests Academy of Natural Sciences as location.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, June 4, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Archaeological Institute of Great Britain and Ireland
    [London] A.L.S.: Arthur H. Lyell 1p. Cannot exchange publications.
  - Letter to J [Sic] M[inis] Hays, June 4, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Foote, Albert E., Co.
    Phila., L. on postal card 1p. and add. Quotations.
  - Letter to [Alexandre Edouard] M[aurice] Cossmann, June 4, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Copy In French Concerns J.P. Smith's paper on coal measures of Arkansas.
  - Letter to James Perrin Smith, June 4, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Typed L.S. 1p. Copy Asks him to send his paper on coal measures of Arkansas to M. Cossmann.
  - Letter to O[thniel] C[harles] Marsh, June 4, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    Phila., Typed L. with MS. correction 1p. Copy. Concerns Cope Memorial Meeting.